Charles Fries

Website: charlesfri.es | Email: charliefries@icloud.com | Phone: +1 (916) 801-9352 GitHub: github.com/charlesfries | LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/charlesfries

SUMMARY

Incredibly passionate, committed, and consistent software developer, with a great attitude and productive mindset. More than 4 years of experience working individually on projects and with teams, designing, publishing, and maintaining full stack software applications. Absolutely proficient in developing production systems using web APIs, databases, MVC principles, automated deployments, source control, and more.

EXPERIENCE

Web Application Developer - McMillan Study Guides, Inc. - San Luis Obispo, CA - 04/2018 to Present

- Developed educational software used by US Air Force members.
- Designed, implemented, integrated, and tested core application services using Ember.js, Broccoli.js, JSONWebTokens, and other frameworks/libraries/protocols.
- Maintained existing production codebases, such us our primary sales web application, to ensure site reliability and accessibility for our customers.
- Spearheaded development of various components, such as our string management service, static asset management system, and frontend authentication/authorization protocol.

Co-Founder – Shiftcode Inc. – San Luis Obispo, CA – 12/2016 to 04/2018

- Coordinated technology and engineering for a software development business called Shiftcode Inc. (https://shiftco.de)
- Interviewed and recruited subcontractors for programming and graphic design work; analyzed project details and established timelines in order to meet goals set by customers; delegated tasks accordingly.
- Ensured timely delivery of software products to customers.
- Development contracts included Simpol (an order management system for bars and restaurants), Arkitu (a farmers' market companion app), and PrepUp (an SAT/ACT practice website for students).
- 9 other projects: Arkitu, CloudSocial, Crytq, Heavenly Weather, PrepUp, Rated, Simpol, Smart Readers, and TextHippo

Cashier – Emigh Hardware Company – Sacramento, CA – 05/2013 to 08/2014 – High School Job

- Responsibilities included assisting customers and selecting the appropriate tools and parts for a variety of projects.
- Counted money in cash drawers to ensure that amounts were correct and adequate change was present for subsequent shifts.
- Maintained the merit of being the store's youngest employee.

SKILLS

Languages: **PHP**, **Swift**, **JavaScript**, SQL, HTML/CSS Frameworks: Ember.js, Node.js, CakePHP, jQuery, Bootstrap Systems: **Ubuntu**, **iOS**, macOS, Debian

Applications: Git, Nginx, SSH, npm, CocoaPods, blockchain

Databases: **MySQL**, MSSQL, MongoDB Providers: AWS, Google Cloud, standard VPS

PROJECTS

SwiftyFetch - Swift CocoaPod

• Developer of SwiftyFetch, a CocoaPod for programmatically making asynchronous web requests on iOS.

Lumitrade – Web Application

• Developer of Lumitrade, a investment portfolio management tool for tracking and sharing investment strategies.

ember-wildcard – Ember Addon

• Developer of ember-wildcard, an Ember service that verifies equality between strings that contain arbitrary data.

Strum - iOS Application

 Developer of Strum, an iOS application that uses the iOS system clock to sync audio between many devices without any network, Bluetooth, or NFC communication between them.

EDUCATION